<!--
 ~ The MIT License
 ~
 ~ Copyright (c) 2017, CloudBees, Inc.
 ~
 ~ Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a copy
 ~ of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"), to deal
 ~ in the Software without restriction, including without limitation the rights
 ~ to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell
 ~ copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the Software is
 ~ furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:
 ~
 ~ The above copyright notice and this permission notice shall be included in
 ~ all copies or substantial portions of the Software.
 ~
 ~ THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
 ~ IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
 ~ FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE
 ~ AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
 ~ LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM,
 ~ OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN
 ~ THE SOFTWARE.
 -->
<div>
    <p>
        This setting allows users to change the default durability mode for running Pipelines.  In most cases this is a
        trade-off between performance and the ability for running pipelines to resume after unplanned Jenkins outages.

        <br><br><strong>What does this do?</strong>
        <ul>
            <li>Previously, running pipelines wrote data constantly, so that they could resume even if Jenkins fails.
                This setting gives the user the ability to adjust this write behavior.</li>
            <li>Higher-performance/lower-durability modes write data to disk <strong>much</strong> less often for running pipelines.</li>
            <li>Writing data less often can massively reduce build times for Pipelines with many steps or complex logic.
                For pipelines which spend most of their time waiting for a shell/batch script to run, the difference will be less visible.</li>
            <li>Running pipelines with lower durability settings may lose data <strong>if</strong> they do not finish and Jenkins is not shut down gracefully:</li>
            <ul>
                <li>A "graceful" shutdown where Jenkins goes through a full shutdown process, such as visiting <code>http://[jenkins-server]/exit</code></li>
                <li>A "dirty" shutdown, such as using <code>kill -9</code> to terminate the Jenkins process, may prevent incomplete pipelines from persisting data</li>
            </ul>
            <li>Pipelines that cannot persist data may not be able to resume or displayed in Blue Ocean/Stage View/etc.</li>
            <li>Pipelines will generally write log data regardless of durability settings.</li>
            <li>Some modes use an "atomic write" option - this helps ensure that pipeline build files aren't overwritten or left partially written if something fails.</li>
            <li>Atomic writes may place more stress on filesystems, so especially with networked storage it may be faster not to use them.</li>
        </ul>
    </p>
    <p>
        <strong>Note: </strong> defaults may be set globally under Manage Jenkins > Configure System.
    </p>
</div>